REBECCA WOLFE

DATA ANALYST

rebeccagwolfe@gmail.com

973-271-1051

Nashville, TN

linkedin.com/in/rebeccagwolfe

github.com/rebeccagwolfe

SKILLS

- SQL (PostgreSQL)
- Spreadsheets
- Python
- Power BI
- Tableau

PROJECTS

Clinical Calculator

- Used Excel to develop a spreadsheet that calculates tube feeding formula requirements and anthropometric data of pediatric patients
- Incorporates DRI and RDA data
- Allows for customization of tube feeding regimen
- Saves time and decreases likeliness of error
- Utilized daily by myself and my colleagues

App Trader

- Used SQL gueries to determine most profitable
- Created visuals to display data

Elderly Assistance

- Evaluated tax data using Excel to determine ways to provide resources to best assist elderly tax payers
- Created interactive dashboard

Nashville City Cemetery

- Cleaned and analyzed data from the Nashville City Cemetery using Excel
- Provided marketing materials to promote the cemetery using deductions based on data
- Created interactive dashboard

SUMMARY

Curious, creative, critical thinker committed to solving problems using datadriven solutions. With a background in nutrition and data analytics, I bring a unique perspective to the healthcare industry. I am passionate about innovation and research. I strive to create the best dashboards and tools in order to help healthcare organizations and staff perform as effectively and efficiently as possible.

EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYST APPRENTICESHIP

Nashville Software School [Nashville, TN]

July 2022 - Present

July 2020-Present

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and Power BI
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project

CLINICAL REGISTERED DIETITIAN

Monroe Carell Jr Children's Hospital at Vanderbilt [Nashville, TN]

- Conduct nutrition assessments for pediatric patients in the outpatient gastroenterology clinic
- Highest billing dietitian in the entire pediatric nutrition department
- Routinely engage in motivational interviewing for weight management
- Intervene, educate, and follow up with patients based on their nutritional
- Developed and maintain an excel spreadsheet that helps dietitians quickly calculate tube feeding formula requirements and anthropometric data for our pediatric patients
- Utilize EPIC electronic medical record system to chart on patient encounters, communicate with patients, and run productivity reports

FORMULA ROOM MANAGER

Monroe Carell Jr Children's Hospital at Vanderbilt [Nashville, TN] Dec 2016- Jul 2020

- Managed formula room staff and directed operational functions to ensure that infant feedings are procured, stored, prepared, labeled, and delivered
- Led onboarding and training for all new and current employees
- Created and enforced new policies which decreased likeliness of error and increased efficiency
- Designed a website using conditional branching to streamline communication processes between medical professionals
- Oversaw Implementation and deployment of EPIC Go Live from StarPanel medical record system

Money Talks

- Created visually captivating dashboard using Tableau to display dataset of Data Science & Analytics salaries
- Incorporated interactive features, which slices data based on experience level, remote vs inperson preference, and sub-fields of Data Science & Analytics

Our Future Writers

- Designed a dashboard with slicers to drill down on the authors based on their grade, poem title, and text
- Utilized Power BI to import, transpose, and create a star schema of a dataset of elementary school poems
- Provided insights to pediatric content creators in regards to the most popular topics based on grade

GDP & Internet Usage

- Imported csv files into dataframes in Jupyter Notebooks
- Performed exploratory data analysis on GDP and internet use statistics
- Used python packages, such as pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, and NumPy to analyze data and create visualizations
- Made insights and identified trends based on my analysis

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School - Nashville, TN

- Data Analytics Bootcamp Certification
- July 2022 Present

NHC Dietetic Internship - Nashville, TN

- 1200 supervised practice hours
- Aug 2014 June 2015

Lipscomb University - Nashville, TN

- Bachelor of Science, Dietetics Major, GPA 3.8
- Magna Cum Laude
- Aug 2010 May 2014

- Created a novel system within HealthTouch, which optimized infant formula recipe calculation
- Collaborated with project managers for the duration of multiple system updates within HealthTouch
- Successfully maintained Tennessee State mandatory health regulations at all times and passed every inspection under my tenure
- Functioned as co-manager of the formula room and pulmonary outpatient clinic dietitian from July 2019 to July 2020

REGISTERED DIETITIAN

National HealthCare Corporation [McMinnville, TN & Sparta, TN] Aug 2015–Dec 2016

- Spearheaded programs that cut unintentional weight loss by nearly 70%
- Conducted nutrition assessments for two Long Term Care/Skilled Nursing Facilities totaling over 180 residents
- Implemented and maintained systems within nursing and dietary departments to prevent malnutrition
- Coordinated with multiple departments to accomplish corporate-wide nutrition goals
- Customized an 8 week select menu system to meet the needs, demographics, and preferences respective to each facility
- Designed and routinely performed patient satisfaction surveys and tray audits in order to collect data and make appropriate changes

DIET TECH

NHC Place, Cool Springs [Franklin, TN]

Jan 2014-Aug 2014

- Visited patients to assess food preferences, allergies, and menu type
- Managed the tray card and menu system for 150 continuing care and rehab patients
- Supervised the count of portions needed for the cooks' production sheets

PROFESSIONAL VIOLINIST/FIDDLER

North Jersey & Middle Tennessee Area

2006-Present

- Perform regularly with a bluegrass band at events and venues such as Westhaven Porch Fest, Third & Lindsley, Country Music Hall of Fame, Tin Roof Nashville, Pilgrimage Music Festival, and was featured on channel 4 "Today in Nashville" highlight
- Perform periodically at weddings and other special events and have maintained a 5 star rating from across all bookings
- Perform regularly in various church worship bands where I write my own arrangements
- Have arranged variety of trios/quartets/duos for various events using violin, viola, cello, bass, guitar, mandolin, and banjo
- Have Performed as studio violinist featured on multiple albums
- Minored in violin performance in college and awarded a music scholarship
- Toured Germany playing fiddle in a gospel bluegrass band
- Mastered classical violin, auditioned, and was accepted into Regions Orchestra of North Jersey
- Auditioned for and was awarded Associate Concertmaster in high school orchestra
- Featured violin soloist on high school orchestra European tour